A Guide to the Ruth Daigon Papers 1970.0004
Archives & Special Collections at the Thomas J. Dodd Research Center, University of Connecticut Library
Ruth Daigon Papers
1966-2007
Archives & Special Collections at the Thomas J. Dodd Research Center, University of Connecticut Library
1970.0004
8.50 Linear Feet
Ruth Daigon, an award-winning American poet, singer and editor, was born in Winnipeg, Manitoba, Canada. Her career in music as a soprano brought her into contact with New York Pro Musica, appearances on Columbia recordings, CBS-TV, recitals and tours. Ruth Daigon's poetry has been published in hundreds of literary magazines and in several anthologies. Ruth Daigon died on February 17, 2010.
Biography
Ruth Daigon, an award-winning American poet, singer and editor, was born in Winnipeg, Manitoba, Canada. She received a B.A. with honors from the University of Manitoba. Her career in music as a soprano brought her into contact with New York Pro Musica, appearances on Columbia recordings, CBS-TV, recitals and tours. Her poetry has been published in hundreds of literary magazines and in several anthologies, including the De Kalb Literary Art Journal Anthology, Shenandoah, The Southern Review, and Poetry Now. Until 1996, when the Daigons moved to California, Ms. Daigon and her husband, Arthur, lived in Chaplin, Connecticut, where she also edited and published Poets on, a poetry magazine. Ruth Daigon died at her home in Corte Madera, California on February 17, 2010.
Scope and Content
The collection consists of nearly three decades of poetry by Daigon. Poems are arranged by year of composition. The collection also contains the author's correspondence with publishers in regard to her work and 23 notebooks of drafts. Materials used in the publication of Poets on are housed separately.
Two folders of personal materials have been restricted by the donor. These materials may only be accessed with the author's heirs written permission.
Access
The collection is open and available for research, except for two folders of personal materials that have been restricted by the donor. These materials may only be accessed with the written permission of the heirs.
Publications (documents); Notebooks; Poets; Musicians; Personal papers; Correspondence; Manuscripts (document genre)
- Series I: Poetry, undated, 1966-1980
  - Poetry, 1966-1968 (Box 1:, Folder 1)
  - Published works, 1968-1970 (Box 1:, Folder 2)
  - Poetry, 1969 (Box 1:, Folder 3)
  - Poetry, 1969 (Box 1:, Folder 4)
  - Poetry, 1970 (Box 1:, Folder 5)
  - Poetry, 1970 (Box 1:, Folder 6)
  - Poetry, 1970 (Box 1:, Folder 7)
  - Poetry, 1970 (Box 1:, Folder 8)
  - Poetry, 1971 (Box 2:, Folder 9)
  - Poetry, 1972 (Box 2:, Folder 10)
  - Poetry, 1972 (Box 2:, Folder 11)
  - Poetry, 1973 (Box 2:, Folder 12)
  - Poetry, 1974 (Box 2:, Folder 13)
  - Poetry, 1974 (Box 2:, Folder 14)
  - Poetry, 1974 (Box 2:, Folder 15)
  - Poetry, 1975 (Box 3:, Folder 16)
  - Poetry, 1975 (Box 3:, Folder 17)
  - Poetry, 1975 (Box 3:, Folder 18)
  - "Learning Not to Kill You", 1975 (Box 3:, Folder 19)
  - Poetry, 1980 (Box 3:, Folder 20)
  - Poetry, 1980 (Box 3:, Folder 21)
  - Poetry, 1980 (Box 3:, Folder 22)
  - Poetry, 1980 (Box 3:, Folder 23)
  - Poetry and music, 1980 (Box 3:, Folder 24)
  - Poetry, undated (Box 3:, Folder 25)
  - Poetry **RESTRICTED**, 1966 (Box 3:, Folder 26)
  - Poetry **RESTRICTED**, 1967-69 (Box 3:, Folder 27)
  - Looking Glass Competition, undated (Box 3:, Folder 28)
  - "Nude among the Statuary", undated (Box 3:, Folder 29)
- Series II: Correspondence, undated, 1966-1981
  - Re Publication, 1966-1970 (Box 3:, Folder 30)
- Series III: Notebooks, 1967-1981
  - Notebook I, 1967 January - May (Box 4:, Folder 31)
  - Notebook II, 1967 June - August (Box 4:, Folder 32)
  - Notebook III, 1967 September - December (Box 4:, Folder 33)
  - Notebook IV, 1968 January - June (Box 4:, Folder 34)
  - Notebook V, 1968 January - June (Box 4:, Folder 35)
  - Notebook VI, 1969 November - January (Box 4:, Folder 36)
  - Notebook VII, 1969 February - May (Box 4:, Folder 37)
  - Notebook VIII, 1969 June - October (Box 4:, Folder 38)
  - Notebook IX, 1970 November - March (Box 5:, Folder 39)
  - Notebook X, 1970 March - August (Box 5:, Folder 40)
  - Notebook XI, 1970 August (Box 5:, Folder 41)
  - Notebook XII, 1972 February (Box 5:, Folder 42)
  - Notebook XIII, 1972 December - 1973 April (Box 5:, Folder 43)
  - Notebook XIV, 1973 May - October (Box 5:, Folder 44)
  - Notebook XV, 1974 September (Box 5:, Folder 45)
  - Notebook XVI, 1975 January (Box 6:, Folder 46)
  - Notebook XVII, 1981 Summer (Box 6:, Folder 47)
  - Notebook XVIII, undated (Box 6:, Folder 48)
  - Notebook XIX, undated (Box 6:, Folder 49)
  - Notebook XX, undated (Box 6:, Folder 50)
  - Notebook XXI, undated (Box 6:, Folder 51)
  - Notebook XXII, 1970 - 1973 (Box 7:, Folder 52)
  - Notebook XXIII, 1973 - 1974 (Box 7:, Folder 53)
- Series IV: Poetry Magazine Poets on, 1982-1986
  - 1982 Summer (Box 8:, Folder 54)
  - 1983 Summer (Box 8:, Folder 55)
  - 1983 Winter (Box 8:, Folder 56)
  - 1984 Summer (Box 8:, Folder 57)
  - 1984 Winter (Box 8:, Folder 58)
  - 1985 Summer (Box 8:, Folder 59)
  - 1985 Winter (Box 8:, Folder 60)
  - 1986 Summer (Box 8:, Folder 61)
  - 1986 Winter (Box 8:, Folder 62)
  - Poets on Cover, undated (Box 8:, Folder 63)
- Series: Inventory Accession 2007.0044, 1977-2007
  - Books (36), Correspondence, Clippings, Awards, Post Cards, Photographs, Fliers, 1977-2004 (Box 9)
    Scope and Content Note
    [Subjects include: Published works of Poets On collection from 1977-1996, Biographies about her life, Written work including Between One Future and the Next, Payday at the Triangle, Handfuls of Time and The Moon Inside, Correspondence with other poets as well as publishers, Reviews of her work, Submitted poems and Accomplishments. ]
  - Publications (25), 1976-2007 (Box 10)
    [Subjects include: Books of work include, Kansas Quarterly, Alaska Quarterly, Midwest Quarterly, Anthology One, Room of One's Own, Southern Poetry Review, Prism International, The MacGuffin, Folio, Poet Lore, Literary Magazine Review, Talking River Review, Irrepressible Appetites, Ellipsis, American Women Poets, Hyperion, 75 Poems of Retirement, Mississippi Review, Tamarack Review, The Poetry Review, The Greensboro Review, Eclipse, The Starving Poets Cookbook, The Greenfield Review.]